字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来  我只是个普通的鉴证专员
To the outside world, I'm an ordinary forensic scientist,
但在尖端科研实验室的朋友们的帮助下
but secretly, with the help of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
为了阻止邪恶极速者萨维塔
In an attempt to stop the evil speedster Savitar,
我不小心闯入了未来
I was accidentally thrust into the future,
看到他杀死了我心爱的女人
and I saw him murder the woman that I love.
但是我不会再让这事发生了
But I won't let that happen.
我会尽我一切的努力来改变未来
I'm gonna do everything in my power to change the future,
而我是唯一来得及拯救她的人
and I'm the only one fast enough to keep her alive.
我就是  闪电侠
I am The Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
肯定是超能力者所为
It's definitely a meta.
我觉得这是个新人
I think this is someone new.
对了  我叫西斯科  你就是吉普赛
I'm Cisco, by the way. You must be Gypsy.
-所以就此别过了  -暂且别过
- So this good-bye, then? - For now.
凯特琳  你不想这么做
Caitlin, you do not want to do this.
是时候为自己的行为负责了
Time for me to own who I really am.
你是我认识最强大的人之一
You're one of the strongest people I've ever known.
你能赢得这场斗争
You can win this fight.
-杰西  -不不
- Jesse! - No, no.
-怎么了  -古鲁德
- What's wrong? - Grodd.
抓走了我爸爸
He's got my dad.
他把他关在猩猩城
He has him in Gorilla City.
地球二
闪电侠
第三季
第十三集
他已经失踪两周了
It's been two weeks since he disappeared.
毫无音信
I mean, no one's seen or heard from him since.
慢点  从头说起
Slow down. Just start from the beginning.
你爸爸为什么去猩猩城
Okay, why did your dad go to Gorilla City?
等等  能不能再慢点
Wait, can we slow down even further?
猩猩城是什么
What the hell is a Gorilla City?
好吧
Okay, so...
地球二有一些有意识  高智商的
There are sentient, highly intelligent
进化了的猩猩
evolved gorillas in Earth-2.
它们都生活在非洲中央深处一个城市里
And they all live in a city deep in the heart of Africa.
之前古鲁德追杀菲伊·雷时
We sent Grodd there
我们把它送到了那里
when he went after Fay Wray here.
古鲁德在那里
Grodd's there?
不论在哪个地球  你父亲
Why on Earth, any Earth,
究竟为什么要去那里
would your father want to go there?
我们在我们的尖端科研实验室
I mean, we received a mathematical cryptogram
收到了一个数学密码
at our S.T.A.R. Labs.
非常复杂
It was highly complex.
我爸爸和我花了一周时间才破解
It took a week to decode it, but my dad and I did.
里面说了什么
What did it say?
是一份邀请
It was an invitation
猩猩们发给我爸的
from the gorillas to my dad.
为什么找哈里
Why Harry?
它们想见他
They wanted to meet him.
于是他跟另外十个人就去了
So he mounted an expedition with ten other people,
他们进了丛林
and they went into the jungle.
但是他们几次都没能回复情况
But they failed multiple check-ins,
所以一支搜索队就去找他们
and a search party went in after them.
结果找到的都是尸体
But all they found were the bodies...
都是被活活打死的
all of them beaten to death.
可没有人见到我爸
But no one's seen my dad.
-他是不是...  -不
- I mean, is he-- - No.
不  他还活着  它们
No, he's alive. They--
它们大费周章把他弄去
they went to a lot of trouble to get him there.
肯定是需要他
They need him for something.
我们会查清楚的
We're gonna figure out what that is.
你们在这啊
There you guys are.
我在到处找你们
I've been looking all over for you.
我们是要去喝咖啡吗
Are we going for coffee or what?
爸爸
Dad!
你们看  这才是说早安的正确方式
Yes, that's how you say good morning, people--
要拥抱  你好
with hugs. Hi!
杰西  他不是你父亲
Jesse, that's not who you think it is.
他是HR
This is H.R.
你们上次离开前见过他一面
You met him briefly before you left last time.
乐意效劳  女士
At your service, madame.
他是替代哈里在这里的
He's Harry's replacement.
应该说比哈里强
Some would say improvement.
这是哈里的女儿
This is Harry's daughter.
-对  -他被绑架了
- Yeah. - He's been kidnapped.
他...我不知道  我很抱...
He... I didn't know. I'm so s...
-我以为...  -抱歉
- I thought... - Sorry about that.
我也很抱歉
I'm sorry, too.
抱歉让你又难过了
I'm sorry I took the smile from your face.
你在想什么
What are you thinking about?
未来
The future.
大猩猩袭击后  城市仍在恢复
这是未来的一个标题
This headline from the future:
大猩猩袭击后  城市仍在恢复
the city's still recovering from a gorilla attack.
你觉得这个标题
So you're thinking this headline
和哈里被绑架有关
and Harry being taken are tied together.
肯定不是巧合  对吧
I mean, it can't be a coincidence, right?
哈里被引诱到猩猩城
Harry getting lured to Gorilla City?
古鲁德肯定在策划着什么
Grodd must be planning something.
看来它打算回到这个地球
Seems like he's planning to come back to this Earth.
而且听起来不只是它自己回来
And not alone, by the sound of it.
如果我们救了哈里  也许就能阻止
If we rescue Harry, then maybe that stops
古鲁德在这里的计划
whatever Grodd's planning here,
也许就能改变未来
and maybe that changes the future.
也就能改变我的未来
Which would change my future.
所以救哈里  就能救爱瑞丝
So we save Harry, we save Iris.
但你不确定
But you're not sure.
是的  但是
No, but...
无论如何我都会去
I'm going either way.
哈里是我的朋友  我不会就这么放弃他
Harry's my friend. I'm not gonna just abandon him.
我要回地球二
I'm going back to Earth-2.
我想你会希望有人和你一起去
And I suppose you'll want somebody to come with you
帮你打开缺口吧
who's gonna open those breaches for you?
上次我们配合得很开心
We had so much fun last time.
有点开心  我也去
Fun-ish. I'm in.
我也要去
I'm gonna come too.
我和古鲁德之间有一种特殊的联系
I have a special connection with Grodd.
也许我们可以利用这点来说服它
Maybe we can use that to get through to him.
-对  好  -好  我也去
- Yes, okay. - Great, yeah, I'm coming too.
不行  抱歉  杰西  不行
No. I'm sorry, Jesse, no.
我来这里  不是想让你们去冒所有的险
Look, I didn't come here for you to take all the risk.
我要帮忙
I'm going to help.
如果我让你一起去  你爸爸会杀了我的
Your dad would kill me if I let you come along.
我现在是极速者了
I'm a Speedster now, okay?
我可以照顾自己
I can take care of myself.
我知道  所以我需要你留在这里
I know, which is exactly why I need you to stay here.
我们不在的时候  这城市需要有人保护
I mean, this city needs protecting while we're gone.
另外  你也许可以教沃利一两招
Besides, maybe you can teach Wally a thing or two.
等等  他在说什么
Wait, what is he talking about?
你现在也是极速者了
So you're-- you're a Speedster now.
是啊  我们现在都是极速者了
Yeah, we're both Speedsters now.
太好了  那真是...
Great, yeah, that's, uh...
太棒了
that's awesome.
我以为她听到了会更激动
I, um-- I thought she'd be more excited than that.
中城警局
朱利安  这几天上班的时候
Hey, Julian, would youaybe able to cover for me
你能帮我掩护一下吗
at work for the next few days?
几天  为什么
Few days? Why?
我只是有点事...
I-- I just, um, have a thing--
我们...只是
we're-- it's just--
是闪电侠的事
it's Flash stuff.
比如说
Such as?
我们在平行地球的一位朋友失踪了
A friends of ours is lost on a parallel Earth,
我们要去找他
and we're gonna go get him back.
-平行地球  -是的
- A parallel Earth? - Yeah.
就是多元宇宙
This is the-- this is the multiverse.
我很有兴趣
I'm fascinated.
你经常穿越去其他的地球吗
And do you often travel to other Earths?
不  我只有必要时会去
No, I-- well, when I have to.
朱利安  你能和辛格说
Look, Julian, will you just tell Singh that,
我身体不舒服之类的吗
I don't know, I'm under the weather or something?
我们闪电侠小组都这么做
It's-- you know, it is kind of what we do on Team Flash.
大家互相帮忙掩护
We cover for each other.
凯特琳怎么看多元宇宙间往返的事
What does Caitlin think of all this multiverse hopping?
-她赞成吗  -她和我一起去
- Does she approve? - She's coming with me.
-你让她去吗  -是她的选择
- You're letting her go? - It's her choice.
艾伦  这无疑是个不明智的举动
Allen, it's not a wise move, surely.
她几乎无法控制她的超能力
She can barely control her cold powers as is.
-我是说  -我们可能需要她来对付古鲁德
- I mean-- - We might need her for Grodd.
古鲁德  古鲁...
Grodd? Gr--
会心灵感应的大猩猩
Telepathic gorilla?
-是的  -你们要去哪
- Yeah. - Where-- where are you going?
是去人猿星球吗
Are you going to Planet of the Apes?
不  只是一座猩猩城
No, it's just a city of them, okay?
你能帮找掩护吗
Will you cover for me?
你们要去人猿星球吗
Are you going to Planet of the Apes?
我不是要去人猿星球
I'm not going to Planet of the Apes, okay?
别激动  你能帮我掩护吗
Calm down. Will you cover for me?
交给我吧  没问题
I got you. Yeah, of course.
谢谢你  几天后见
Okay, thank you. See you in a few days.
好
All right, now.
-确保沃利不会...  -不会的
- And make sure Wally doesn't-- - I won't.
因为有时他会有点...
Because, you know, sometimes he can be a little--
-巴里  -你知道的
- Barry-- - You know,
一旦有机会
if given the opportunity--
巴里  我最会使唤我弟弟了  好吗
Barry, I am very good at bossing my little brother around, okay?
-不要担心  -好
- Don't worry. - All right.
千万别做傻事
Just please don't do anything stupid.
你是指自愿去超能力猩猩城吗
You mean like voluntarily going to a city of super apes?
我是说真的  去救哈里吧
I'm being serious. Rescue Harry.
但除此之外  你不必为我这么做
But other than that, you-- you don't have to do this for me.
我做的一切都是为了你
Everything I do is for you.
很好
Good.
你们都知道沃利能听见  对吧
Y'all know Wally can hear you, right?
抱歉  沃利
Sorry, Wally.
注意安全
Be safe.
如果感觉不妙  就赶紧跑
You see anything hinky, you run.
听听我说的  不用我再告诉你了
Listen to me. I don't need to tell you that.
-我保证  -好的
- I promise. - All right.
警探
Detective.
《夺宝奇兵》看多了吗
Indiana Jones much?
西斯科  我的朋友  这不是我第一次探险
Cisco, my friend, this is not my first expedition,
相信我  这是最合适的装扮
and believe me, this is the perfect attire.
等等  朱利安  这是怎么回事
Wait, Julian, what's going on?
你不是要给我打掩护吗
I thought you were gonna cover for me.
我和辛格说过了
I spoke to Captain Singh.
他以为我们去了布鲁德海文的形态学研讨会
He thinks we're at a morphology conference up in Bludhaven.
所以如果你不介意的话
So if it's all the same to you...
你不需要来的  朱利安
You don't have to come, Julian.
你都不认识哈里
You don't even know Harry.
有机会穿越到另一个维度
A chance to travel to another dimension--
我可不会错过
I mean, I wasn't gonna miss that.
我们不是去观光的
We're not going sightseeing.
我也不是
Neither am I.
那好吧
Well, damn.
好吧  杰西  沃利
All right, Jesse, Wally,
我不在时  你们确保这里的安全  好吗
you make sure this city's safe while I'm gone, all right?
我们会的
We will.
巴里
Hey, Barry.
如果你见到我爸爸  跟他说...
If you--if you see my dad, just tell him--
你很快会见到他的  杰西
You'll see him real soon, Jesse.
以极速者名誉担保
Speedster's honor.
-好了  咱们走吧  -好的
- All right, let's do this. - Okay.
地球二  我们来了
Earth-2, here we come.
感觉如何
How was that?
太棒了
Bloody brilliant.
我们到了
Well, we made it.
欢迎来到丛林  宝贝
Welcome to the jungle, baby.
地球二的非洲
Earth-2 Africa.
竟然不热
Not hot.
看来全球变暖在这里不是事
Guess global warming's not really a thing here.
但虫子是
But bugs are.
谁来解释一下
Someone please help me out.
为何在这个地球上救一个人
How exactly does saving someone on this Earth
能阻止我们地球上的攻击呢
prevent an attack on ours?
如果古鲁德想要进攻
If Grodd is planning to attack,
他需要打开通向我们地球的缺口
he's gonna need to open a breach to our Earth,
而在这里唯一能打开缺口的人就是...
and the only one over here that can open one is--
-哈里森·威尔斯  -哈里森·威尔斯  对
- Harrison Wells. - Harrison Wells, yeah.
所以如果我们从古鲁德手中救了他
So if we save him from Grodd,
它就来不了我们的地球了
then he can't get to our Earth,
进攻不会发生  我们就改变了未来
the attack never happens, we change the future,
我们也就离救爱瑞丝近了一步
and we're one step closer to saving Iris.
你想去跑一跑吗
You want to go for a run?
行啊  等下吧
Yeah, yeah. Maybe later.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
还好  我挺好的
Yeah. Yeah, I'm fine.
我知道我没怎么跟你保持联系
Look, I know I haven't been great at keeping in touch.
只是最近的事太疯狂了
It's just everything's been so crazy
和巴里一起训练  尾随他
trying to train with Barry and shadowing him,
我没有什么时间想其他事
and I just haven't had that much time for other things.
是啊  或者其他人
Yeah, or other people.
我不是这个意思
That is not what I meant.
别  我懂得  相信我
No, look, I--I get it. Trust me.
当英雄不那么简单  对吧
It's not easy being a hero, is it?
不  但我喜欢极了
No, but I love every minute of it.
那就好
Great.
你确定你没事吗
Are you sure you're okay?
-因为...  -没事
- Because... - Yeah.
我只是很担心我爸爸
I'm just worried about my dad.
希望没有打断你们俩
I hope we didn't interrupt you two.
没有  没什么可打断的
Nope. Nothing to interrupt.
你不...
Aren't you--
她回来了你不高兴吗
you aren't happy she's back?
我很高兴  只是她似乎不那么高兴
I am. I just wish she felt the same.
她这次来了之后  对我的态度就怪怪的
Ever since she got here, she's been acting so weird with me.
我不知道是因为我有了超能力
I--I don't know if it's because I have powers
还是只是因为我
or if it's just me.
沃利  她可能只是难过
Wally, she's probably still just upset
因为她父亲失踪了  懂吗
because her father's missing, right?
是啊  被那么沉重的事压着
Yeah, it's hard to focus on other things
确实很难关注别的事
when something like that is weighing you down.
是的  沃利  她会没事的
Yeah, Wally. She'll be fine.
给她一些时间吧
Just give her some time,
然后  你懂得  一锤定音
and then, you know, lock it down.
-一锤定音  -是啊
- Lock it down, hmm? - Yeah.
怎么  你觉得我没注意到
What, you think I didn't notice
你的脸书资料上还写着"单身"吗
that your Facebook profile still says "Single"?
怎么  理论上我确实还是单身啊
What? I mean, technically, I'm still single.
怎么了
What was it?
奥沙利文银行出现抢劫
Ugh, robbery in progress at O'Sullivan Bank.
你们俩快去
You two go.
快  我们走
Come on, let's go.
-你没看新闻吧  -什么新闻
- Didn't hear the news, huh? - What news?
别惹闪电小子
That you don't mess with Kid Flash.
我们得回我们朋友那里去
We got to get back to our friends.
他们在等着我们
They're expecting us.
他们可真是找了俩厉害的
Yeah, they picked some real winners.
我知道  你俩看起来可不怎么样
I know, which is more than I can say for you two.
马上回来
Be right back.
抱歉  我得活动下腿脚
Sorry, I-- I had to stretch my legs.
大伙  快出来
Hey, guys, come out.
没什么可看的  各位
It's--it's nothing to see here, guys.
就是俩蠢货被人收拾了
It's just a couple fools getting their asses handed to 'em.
谢谢
Thank you.
天啊  谢谢大家
Oh, my gosh, thank you.
要喝点水吗
Want some water?
我没事  谢了
I'm okay, thanks.
在平行地球上保持水分可是很重要的
It's important to stay hydrated on a parallel Earth.
又回到这个平行宇宙的感觉真是奇怪
So weird being back here on this alternate universe.
我就是在这里遇见了我的二重身
This is where I met my doppelganger,
那个邪恶的我
the evil one.
冰霜杀手
Killer Frost.
我一直害怕会变成她那样
She's the one I'm always afraid of becoming.
那她现在在哪
And where is she now?
死了
Dead.
你不会死的  凯特琳
That's not gonna happen to you, Caitlin.
我很高兴你能一起来 朱利安
I'm glad you came with us, Julian.
这个团队有你真好
You're a nice addition to the team.
好吧
Yeah, well,
我喜欢危险的生活
I live for danger.
我们接近了  各位
We're close, guys.
你听到了吗
Do you hear that?
就是这里了
This is it.
这是个陷阱
It's a trap.
欢迎  凯特琳
Welcome, Caitlin.
就知道你会来
Knew you'd come...
闪电侠
Flash.
你们还好吗
You guys all right?
我没事
Yeah, I'm okay.
我也是
Yeah, me too.
我的枪没了  不过我还好
I've lost my gun, but I'm all right.
看起来你得带我们穿墙出去了
Well, looks like you're gonna have to phase us out of here.
我不知道怎么回事  有什么东西在阻拦我
I don't know. Something's holding me back.
你能打开缺口吗
Can you open a breach?
不行
No dice.
我觉得不是牢房的原因
I don't think it's the cell. I...
古鲁德一定是设法抑制了我们的能力
Grodd must be dampening our powers somehow.
好吧
Okay.
哈里
Harry?
你没事
You're all right.
威尔斯
Wells. Hey!
你得帮我们逃出去
You got to help us get out of here
趁那些大猩猩还没回来
before the gorillas come back.
你好啊  闪电侠
Hello, Flash.
-古鲁德  -什么
- Grodd. - What?
那是大猩猩古鲁德吗
That's Grodd the gorilla?
他在通过威尔斯跟我们说话吗
He's talking through Wells?
-这样也行  -是啊
- That's a--a thing? - Yeah.
第一次谁都会懵  不过相信我
Yeah, sort of trips you out at first, but trust me,
你会习惯的
you get used to it.
古鲁德  放了他
Grodd, let him go.
这是你我之间的事
This is between you and me.
现在还不行
Not yet.
-我需要他  -干什么
- I need him. - For what?
你为什么诱他过来
Why'd you lure him here?
为了你
For you.
需要你的帮助
Need your help.
帮助  你这请求方式可真有趣
Help? Got a funny way of asking for it.
是你把我送来的
You sent me here!
记得吗
Remember?
活在这个地狱里
To live in this hell!
在这里  我被迫服从
Where I am forced to serve
索罗瓦的统治
under the rule of Solovar.
索罗瓦是谁
Who's Solovar?
大猩猩族的族长
Leader of Gorilla Kind.
大猩猩城的统治者
Ruler of Gorilla City.
如今
And now...
他想要统治人类
he wants to rule the humans.
他将会把战争带去你的地球
He will bring war to your Earth.
-为什么  -他看到了很多
- Why? - He has seen many conflicts
大猩猩和人类的争端
between gorillas and humans.
他害怕人类会进攻
He is afraid the humans will attack,
但现在你来了
but now that you're here,
他会把战争引向你
he will bring the fight to you.
所以你诱骗我们来阻止他吗
So you lured us here to stop him?
作为非法入侵者
As trespassers...
你们将会被送到竞技场
you will be sent to the arena
进行处决
and executed.
什么  入口怎么不设个标牌
What? How about a signpost at the front?
"所有入侵者都将被处死"
"All trespassers will be executed."
这主意实在是太糟了  不是吗
That wouldn't be the worst idea, would it?
索罗瓦会很荣幸
Will be Solovar's great honor
能够亲手
to kill you...
杀死你
himself.
但是  闪电侠...
But, Flash...
如果他最终被打败了
if he were to be defeated,
其他猩猩就会发现他的弱小
the other gorillas would see his weakness
不再追随他
and would no longer follow him.
我不会杀死任何人
Well, I'm not gonna kill anyone,
猩猩也不行
not even a gorilla.
不杀就等死
Kill or be killed!
这是猩界唯一的法则
This is the only law Gorilla Kind understands.
你能得到什么好处  古鲁德
How do you benefit from this, Grodd?
索罗瓦倒台了
Solovar falls.
我就能接替他
I take his place.
统领猩猩们
I rule the gorillas,
我保证他们都会呆在猩猩城里
and I promise to keep them in Gorilla City.
我们为什么要相信你
How do we know we can trust you?
因为...
Because...
就算你们把我赶走了
even though you sent me away,
你们的地球仍然是我的家园
your Earth is still my home.
而你们这些人
And there are those among you
我永远也不会忘记
I will never forget.
杀了索罗瓦
Kill Solovar,
中城就会安然无恙
and Central City will be spared.
没做到  那就等着看你的家乡
Fail, and see your home
变为灰烬吧
turned to ash.
杰西  你有空吗
Hey, Jesse, you got a sec?
我是不是做错了什么
Did I do something wrong?
我没  我没觉得
I don't-- I don't think so.
好吧  那你为什么对我这么冷淡
Okay, then why are you being so cold with me?
杰西  你可以跟我聊聊的
Jesse, come on, you can talk to me.
我知道这不仅仅关于你的父亲
I know that this is about more than just your dad.
我觉得...
Look, I guess...
我总是觉得有一天我们会想办法在一起
I guess I thought one day we'd figure out a way to be together.
但现在你有了能力  可是...
You know, but now that you have your powers, it's...
我好像从来没有受到过你的消息
It's like I never hear from you.
杰西  如果可以...
Jesse, if--if you would,
我希望你留下
I want you to stay.
-我做不到  -为什么
- I can't. - Why?
因为你的父亲
Because of your dad?
巴里会找到他的
Because Barry is going to find him.
你不知道的
Look, you don't know that, okay?
你不知道
You don't.
我刚刚得到能力的时候
When I first got my power,
你非常困惑  因为你没有能力
you were so lost not having yours.
我觉得也许你喜欢上我
You know, and I thought maybe part of the reason
部分是因为...
why you liked me was...
是因为你被速度吸引  而不是我
'cause you were attracted to the speed and not me.
我懂的  我懂的  好吗
I know, I know, okay?
但我今天看到你在那里...
But I saw you out there today...
作为闪电小子
being Kid Flash.
你的人生完整了  沃利
Okay, and you were complete, Wally.
完整得不能再完整了
You were scary complete.
我可以变成世界上最快的人
I could have all the speed in the world.
但没有你我就不完整
I'm not complete without you.
留下
Stay.
巴里  你真的能杀掉这个索罗瓦吗
Barry, do you really think you could kill this Solovar?
你真能下得去手吗
Do you think you could take a life?
这正是我担心的
It is as I feared.
人类来找猩界宣战了
The humans court war with Gorilla Kind.
为什么不告诉我  古鲁德
Why did you not tell me, Grodd,
有更多的人类进了城
more humans had entered the city?
我正准备告诉您  索罗瓦
I was about to inform you, Solovar.
为什么  为什么你们在这
Why? Why are you here?
来把我们像动物一样进行研究吗
To study us like animals?
-把我们变成你们的宠物  -不  不
- Make us your pets? - No, no.
我是...
I'm--I...
我们是为和平而来
We came here in peace.
我们是误入了你的城市
We entered your city by mistake.
我们没想伤害你们
Uh, we mean you no harm.
请...
Please...
放我和我的朋友走  我保证
just let me and my friends go, and I promise,
我们再也不会回来
we'll never come back here again.
我的弟兄们见过你们
My brethren have seen you.
你们的命运无法改变
Your fate is sealed.
你们都会死在我的手里
You will all die by my hand...
死在竞技场
in the arena...
这样所有人都会见识到索罗瓦的公正
so that all will know that Solovar's justice
是如此智慧而果断
is wise and swift.
好吧  不如这样
All right, I'll make you a deal.
我在竞技场和你打  只有我
I'll fight you in the arena-- just me.
但如果我打赢了  你就得放了我的朋友
But if I beat you, you let my friends go,
而且再也不来找我们
and you leave us alone for good.
我接受
I accept.
人类和他们的傲慢
Humans and their arrogance.
你们会先受苦
First you will suffer.
然后我保证你们一个个...
Then I will grant you each...
都会惨死
a horrible death.
极速者对战超级大猩猩
Speedster versus super gorilla.
史上最烂的游戏
Best worst video game ever.
你们觉得巴里可以战胜索罗瓦吗
Do you really think that Barry can beat Solovar?
他最好可以  为我们大家起见
Well, he'd better, for all of our sakes.
开始了
It's starting.
等你死了
After you die,
你的朋友们会跟你陪葬
your friends will follow you into the black.
-走着瞧  -好了  巴里
- We'll see. - Okay, Barry.
我有个计划
I got a plan for you.
先使用快速拳
It's all about the speed punches.
快速拳  上吧  巴里
Speed punches. Come on, Barry.
计划有变  巴里
Change of plan, Barry.
先选择逃跑
It's all about the running away.
用闪电抛掷如何
What aboutbo lightning throw?
对  巴里  闪电抛掷
Yes, Barry, lightning throw!
值得一试
Worth a shot!
两招都不行
That's oh for two.
加油  巴里  站起来
Come on, Barry, get up.
我的天啊  我们的命运要逆转了
All my days, this is quite the reversal of our fortune.
逆转...
Reversal...
巴里  是时候使用逆闪电的招式了
Barry, it's time to pull a reverse Flash.
出手吧
Do it!
他做到了
He did it!
他竟然做到了
He actually did it.
他真的做到了
He bloody well did it.
我不会杀死他
I won't kill him!
不会的
I won't!
我知道你们都畏惧人类
I know you all fear humans!
你们认为人类想和猩猩种族开战
You think we want war with Gorilla Kind!
我们不想
We don't!
我们不都是凶犯和杀手
We're not all murderers and killers!
我们只想要和平
We only want peace!
因此我不会夺去你们领袖的性命
Which is why I'm sparing your leader!
我们称之为怜悯
We call it mercy!
解决他
Take him out.
发生什么了
what happened?
祝贺你
Congratulations.
你赢了
You won.
哈里怎么样了
What about Harry?
他还是神经昏迷
He's still catatonic.
-闪电侠  -我赢了
- Flash. - I won.
索罗瓦答应了放我们走
Solovar promised to let us go.
不行
No.
不行  你什么意思
No? What do you...
我不明白
I don't understand.
索罗瓦的话现在不管用了
Solovar's words mean nothing now.
你从来就没想放我们走  是吧
You never had any intentions of letting us go, did you?
我说过  我需要你
I told you I needed you.
单打独斗  我战胜不了索罗瓦
I could not defeat Solovar in combat,
但你可以
but you could.
你做到了  现在我是猩猩城的领袖了
You did, and now I am the ruler of Gorilla City,
所有的猩猩都会追随我
and all the gorillas will follow me.
索罗瓦从没想过要袭击中城
Solovar never wanted to attack Central City.
是你
You do.
你夺走了我的家
You took my home away from me,
现在我要夺回来
and now I will take it back!
猩猩们看到你干了什么  闪电侠
The gorillas saw what you did, Flash.
他们看到你打败了索罗瓦
They saw you defeat Solovar,
现在他们都害怕人类
and now they are afraid of humans
会听从我的一切命令
and will do anything I order,
我要命令他们入侵你们地球
and I will order them to invade your Earth,
你们的城市将化为灰烬
and your city will burn.
这都是你一直在计划的
You were planning this the whole time.
没错
Yes.
父亲把我教得很好
Father taught me well.
要有深谋远虑
Always think ahead.
我有大把时间在你给我造的牢笼里思考
And I had plenty of time to think in cages built by you
然后又是索罗瓦的牢笼
and then by Solovar.
为什么不干脆杀了我们
Then why don't you just kill us?
既然我们已经替你做了坏事
Since we already did your damn dirty work for you.
留你还有用
Still need you.
我不会帮你做任何事的
I'm not doing anything for you.
不是你  闪电侠
Not you, Flash.
是你
You.
我
Me?
你会打开去地球一的缺口
You will open the breach to First Earth.
我的军队会穿过缺口
My army will cross that breach,
中城的所有人类都将
and all the humans in Central City
被我们猩猩种族毁灭
will burn before Gorilla Kind!
古鲁德  你很聪明
Grodd, you are smart,
也许比我们所有人都聪明
maybe smarter than all of us,
你应该知道你不能这么做
smart enough to know that you cannot do this.
智慧和暴力
Intelligence and violence,
是相互对立的存在
they're opposites from each other.
你想做的事  不合乎逻辑
What you want to do, it's not logical,
不是你这样的智慧该做的事
not for someone as wise as you are.
你忘了  闪电侠
You forget, Flash,
我可是个禽兽
I am an animal.
我是一头大猩猩
I am a gorilla.
我们来杀个你死我活
Kill or be killed!
我会逃出这个笼子  阻止你
I'm gonna get out of this cell, and I'm gonna stop you.
不  不可能
No, you won't.
你会死
You will die.
-斯诺  -你没事吧
- Snow? - You okay?
我...
I...
我头有点疼
I have a headache, I guess.
我觉得...  是我吗  我好臭
And I think-- i--is that me? I smell.
应该没什么大碍了
That counts as okay.
杰西  我女儿  她在哪...
Jesse, my daughter. Where's--
她很好  她在地球一上
She's fine. She's on Earth-1.
她一点事也没有
She's totally fine.
巴里
Barry?
西斯科
Cisco.
你们都是为了救我而来的吗
You guys all came for me?
一座城市的邪恶的天才大猩猩
A city of evil genius apes.
听起来很有趣
Sounded like fun.
你们不值得为我这样  但是...
Well, I don't deserve it, but...
谢谢你  斯诺  谢谢你  巴里
thank you, Snow; thank you, Barry,
西斯科
Cisco...
印第安纳
Indiana.
我叫朱利安·艾伯特  谢谢
It's Julian Albert, thank you.
我一起来是因为...
And I came along for--
我为危险而生
I live for danger.
那你可来对地方了
Looks like you came to the right place.
我还是不能穿过这些栏杆
I still can't phase through the bars.
我们得想办法出去  这样才能阻止它
We have to find a way out of here so we can stop him.
你总是这么说  但如果我们出不去呢
You keep saying that, but what if we can't get out?
如果我们被困在这里了呢  如果这是...
What if we're stuck here? What if this is the way--
我们不能往那儿想
Well, we can't think like that.
只要有人活着  就会有希望
While there's life, there's hope.
如果我们都死了呢
And if there isn't life?
这话什么意思
What is that supposed to mean?
古鲁德要我打开一个缺口  它要攻击地球一
Grodd needs me to open the breach so he can attack Earth-1.
如果我在此之前就死了呢
What if I wasn't alive to do that?
你准备去死了吗
You planning on dying?
除非你把我杀了
Only if you kill me.
我们必须把这些考虑进去
Look, this is something we have to consider.
现在  我想不出任何方法阻止它们
Right now, I can't think of any other way to stop them.
它们也没有别的办法去中城
They'd have no other way of getting to Central City.
他说得对
He's right.
西斯科的死会改变未来的新闻头条
Cisco's death would change the newspaper headline in the future.
-头条  -说来话长
- Headline? - It's a long story.
但这也会使另一件事成真
But it would also make another one come true,
关于冰霜杀手的事
the one about Killer Frost.
你想要我来杀死你吗
You want me to kill you?
考虑一下
Think about it.
古德鲁不知道你有冰冻能力
Grodd doesn't know you have cold powers.
-你有机会用用了  -冰冻能力
- You might be able to use them. - Cold powers?
她  你有冰冻能力
She-- you have cold powers?
我就知道  我就知道我和你
I knew it. I knew that you and I
没有把巴里拉出那面镜子
did not get Barry out of that mirror.
等下  凯特琳  如果你杀了人
Wait, now. Caitlin. If you kill someone,
就不能回头了
there's no going back.
你余生都会背负着冰霜杀手的名号
You'll be Killer Frost for the rest of your life.
我大老远到这来要的不是这个结果
Now, I did not come all this way to see that happen.
你来这里不是因为你"为危险而生"吗
Did you come here because you "Live for danger"
还是说你是来保护我的
or to protect me?
我只是不希望你变成你不想成为的人
I just don't want to see you become something you're not.
好吧  西斯科
Okay, Cisco.
我不会杀了你的  谁也不会  好吗
I'm not gonna kill you, and neither is anyone else, okay?
所以我们来想一个万全之策
So let's come up with the next best plan
不用去杀害自己好朋友的万全之策
that doesn't involve murdering one of our friends.
不  西斯科说得对
No, Cisco's right.
这是唯一的办法
It's the only way.
我们中一定要有个人死
One of us has to die.
你在这里做什么
What you doing up there?
就是打发一下时间
Just, uh, hanging out.
你在  你在想什么
What're you-- what're you thinking about?
沃利  他希望我留下来陪他
Wally. He wants me to stay here with him.
他当然想了
Yeah, he does.
男人都很无脑  祝贺你
Guy is no dummy. Congratulations.
真好  爱情...
Oh, that's great. Love...
没什么比得上年轻人的爱情
Nothing like young love.
我就是...  我不...
Yeah, I just-- I don't--
我不知道这样做对不对
I don't know if it's the right thing.
为什么
Why?
他有自己的使命
He's on his own journey.
再说了  我爸被猩猩抓走了
Besides, my dad just got captured by gorillas.
如果他回来了
And if-- if he does come back,
我怎么能告诉他我要离开
how could I ever tell him I'm leaving?
因为你是人类
Well, 'cause you're human.
这就是原因
That's--that's how.
人类就是这样的  听着  我的意思是说
That's what we do. Look, my point is this.
遇见了真爱  就要勇敢追求
When it comes to love, you got to go for it.
你知道吗  其它事都要抛在一边
You know? Everything else be damned.
因为如果你不这么做
'Cause if you don't,
你就会变成一个
you're gonna end up being the kind of person
带着遗憾过完余生的人
that lives the rest of their life with regret.
我知道  要告诉你爸爸
I mean, I know that telling your dad that, you know, you're--
你要去另一个地球
you're switching Earths,
那会是一场很艰难的对话
that's gonna be a difficult conversation to have,
但如果你想要幸福
but one that you've to go for
就必须这么争取
if you want to be happy.
不过这只是我的想法
But that's, you know, just my opinion.
我知道什么呢
What do I know?
我只是个比你爸爸更英俊的
I'm just a handsomer guy than your dad
心中有歌的人
with a song in his heart.
祝你好运  杰西
Good luck, Jesse.
他突然开始咳嗽  咳得很厉害
He started coughing... violently.
然后他捂着身体一边  倒下了
And then he clutched his side and keeled over.
他的伤
The injury...
一定是其中一边肾脏破裂了
it must have ruptured one of his kidneys.
他休克了
He went into shock.
心跳停止了
His heart stopped.
我没法让他醒过来
I couldn't resuscitate him.
冷了
Cold.
他死了
He's dead.
他本来也对我没什么用
He was of no use to me anyway.
他走了  巴里
He's gone, Barry.
古鲁德走了
Grodd is gone.
快醒过来  伙计
Come on, mate.
成功了
Yo, it worked!
It worked.
艾伦  艾伦  你还好吧  伙计
Allen, Allen, you all right, mate?
还好  还好  我没事
Yeah. Yeah, I'm good.
我没把你冻过头吧
I didn't freeze you too much, did I?
没有  我没事
No. I'm good.
这样的话
Well, then...
我们赶快离开这儿吧
let's get the hell out of here.
好
Yeah.
快走
Go!
-好  -万岁
- All right. - Hallelujah.
我们走
Let's go.
好的
All right.
我们应该跑得够远了
We should be far enough out
超能力应该能用了
that you should be able to use your powers.
我们需要马上开一个缺口
We need a breach open right now.
各位  我们得在他们发现之前跑掉
Guys, we got to go before they realize we're gone!
太晚了
It's too late for that.
-跑  -快跑
- Run! - Run!
打开缺口
Open a breach!
是时候穿越这个疯人院了
Time to warp out of this madhouse.
好了  走吧
All right, go.
大伙  谁想把烦恼放一放
Hey, gang, who wants to take their mind off their troubles
玩一个"绝对把烦恼放一放"的字谜游戏
with a "Sure to take your mind off your troubles" Game of charades?
我先来
I'll go first.
好  我们看看
Okay, ah, let's see.
电影  我是说
Movie--I mean...
一个词
one word.
爸爸
Dad!
-你没事吧  -是的  很好
- You okay? - Good, yeah.
很遗憾你们错过了
I'm sorry you guys missed it.
我可不遗憾
I ain't.
一句忠告
Word of advice:
别主动参与这种事
don't volunteer for these things.
没什么东西会想把你大卸八块
Nothing ever tries to rip you limb from limb
除非你主动送上门
if you don't volunteer.
我很好  我非常好  谢谢
I'm fine. I'm so fine, thanks--
谢谢我们的朋友
thanks to our friends,
我们的好朋友
our good friends.
不客气  哈里
You're welcome, Harry.
我想
I--I think--
我忘记你有多英俊了
I just forgot how handsome you were.
我忘了
Oh, I forgot.
他...  你还在这儿
He's-- you're still here.
是的  还在
Yeah. Still here.
我猜我们该感谢你的天才战术和技术
I guess we have your tactical and technical genius
帮我们解了围
to thank for getting us out of that fix.
不  不  没有
No, no, nah.
-没有吗  -没有
- Nah? - Nah.
你对他的判断完全正确
You were completely right about him.
他完全是个骗子  连科学家都不是
He's a total fraud. He's not even a scientist.
而且你肯定连取款密码都记不住
And I'm sure you couldn't even remember an ATM code if you tried.
那么多数字呢
All those-- all those numbers.
一共就四位数  他为什么还在这儿
It's only four digits. Why is he still here?
因为我们离不开他
Because we couldn't do it without him.
谢谢你  三藩西斯科
I thank you, Francisco.
三藩...  三藩西斯科
Fran-- Francisco?
别问了
Don't ask.
对了  在那边发生了什么
Yo, so what actually happened?
你们和绝顶聪明的大猩猩斗了吗
You fight some really super-smart apes, or what?
是的  没错
Yeah. Yeah, we did.
他们的确很聪明  但至少今天
And they were smart, but today, at least,
我们要更聪明一点
we were a bit smarter.
他怎么样了
How's he doing?
他会没事的
He's gonna be okay.
他身上有一些伤口和青肿
He's got some cuts and bruises,
凯特琳说他吃东西和休息就会好
but Caitlin said he just needs food and a little sleep.
好吧
Okay.
我...
Hey, I'm...
我很抱歉这阵子我太失控了
I'm sorry for being an epic basket case lately.
我的爸爸被绑架过
My, um...my dad was kidnapped once,
改变了你的世界
and it turns your world.
你改变了我的世界  沃利
You turn my world, Wally.
我要你跟我老实说件事
Look, I--I need you to be honest about something.
当然没问题
Of course.
如果我在我爸睡醒时跟他说我爱他
When my dad wakes up, if I tell him that I love him
我永远都是他的女儿
and I'll always be his daughter
但我要搬到地球一
but that I want to move to Earth-1,
你有什么想法
what would you think about--
那就是我的想法
That's what I think of that.
我很高兴我们想法一致
I'm glad we think alike.
看来你...
I see you're--
你接受了我的爱情建议
you took my love advice.
当需要科学建议时
You know, when it comes to scientific advice,
我的建议有时会似是而非
mine is sometimes specious,
但需要心灵方面的建议时
but when it comes to affairs of the heart,
我觉得我是这方面的天才
well, I consider myself a genius.
好吧  我们现在得走了
Okay, yeah, we're gonna go now.
好吧  很好
Okay, great.
恭喜你们  我为你们感到很高兴
Congratulations. I'm happy for you.
邀请我去参加婚礼吧
Invite me to the wedding.
他肯定会很生气
He's gonna be so pissed.
凯特琳
Caitlin.
等一下
Wait.
如果我越界了
Listen, if I overstepped,
那我很抱歉
then I apologize.
那晚喝完酒之后...
Just, after drinks the other night--
你愿意为我冒险吗
You were willing to risk your life for me?
我最近做了不少蠢事
I've been doing a lot of silly things recently.
我想再干多一件也无碍
I thought adding one more to the list wouldn't do any harm.
我喜欢你  朱利安
I like you, Julian.
没错
I do.
我喜欢你喜欢我
And I like that you like me.
但我怕我的超能力
But I'm also afraid of my powers--
不是怕它们会伤害我
and not what they could do to me,
但怕它们会伤害跟我亲近的人
but what they could do to anyone who gets close to me.
凯特琳  我不怕
Caitlin, I'm not afraid.
你应该害怕
You should be.
害怕我  朱利安
Fear me, Julian.
不是在威胁你  只是
It's not a threat, just...
善意的提醒
good advice.
那好吧
Okay, fine.
我会害怕你
I'll fear you.
你知道什么能在我害怕时帮我吗
You know what really helps me when I'm scared?
什么
What?
一份好吃的菲力牛排
Just a good fillet steak...
旁边放点鸡蛋黄油酱
bit of béarnaise on the side,
土豆泥
mashed potatoes--
每次都能行
does the trick ever time.
-真的吗  -我向你保证
- Really? - I promise.
我们在当地找家牛排餐厅
I think we should find a local steak house
一起害怕吧
and be terrified together.
没问题  我们一起
Sure. Together it is.
好吧
Well...
-我们做到了  -你做到了
- We did it. - You did it.
不  大家一起做到了
No, uh, we all did it.
我们改变了未来  却没改变自己
We changed the future without changing who we are.
如果我们能继续这么做
If we can keep doing this,
我们就能阻止萨维塔
we can stop Savitar.
不管他在哪里  不管他怎么对付我们
Wherever he is, however he's gonna come at us,
我都能阻止他
I can stop him.
我现在知道了
I know it now.
-你怎么做到的  -做到什么
- How do you do that? - Do what?
在几乎没有胜算时保持乐观
Stay positive in the face of overwhelming odds.
因为我打算跟你一起长寿
Because I plan on living a long life with you,
什么也无法阻止我
and nothing's gonna take that away from me.
很好
Good.
所以你不会再做恶梦了吗
So does that mean no more nightmares?
你今晚终于能好好睡一觉了吗
You're finally gonna get some sleep tonight?
最后这个部分就全靠你了
Well... that last part is entirely up to you.
就像我跟闪电侠说的
Like I told Flash,
要深谋远虑
always think ahead.
现在你将打开缺口
Now you will open the breaches
很快地
and very soon,
中城就会在古鲁德面前倒下
Central City will fall before Grodd.